翻译  cheryl  依俊听杰
翻译  香茗小焙  arie
翻译  大嘴  肉松
校对  喃喃
时间轴  今  dreamdragon  永远的永远  Spohy
后期  8T   虫虫不咬人     总监  喃喃
我给你说  绝对  屡试不爽
Works every -- I'm telling you -- every time.
-得了吧  -来  试试
- No. - Do it. Try it.
-什么  现在吗  -快来
- What? Right now? - Right here.
好吧  那就试试
All right, all right.
凑合
Kind of.
还差点  仍需努力啊  哥们
Yeah, kind of that. Got to work on it, bro.
-好吧  -真差得远
- All right, man. - Seriously.
酒吧
好  我再加把劲
All right, bro, I'll work on it.
但...  你一般什么时候...
But -- but just, like, when -- when do you, you know...
就赶在木塞弹开之前
Right before the cork pops, you know?
时机的确重要  但
Timing's important, but...
但你不能冲着她耳朵嚎吧
but you don't do it, like, in her ear or nothing.
-对  不能冲着耳朵嚎  -没错
- No, you don't do it in her ear. - Because -- Yeah.
当然不能对着耳朵吼
It's a given you don't do it in her ear.
但这是有科学依据的好吗
But this is, like, scientifically proven, okay?
-是吗  -史前就有了
- Really? - This is, like, prehistoric stuff.
-人脑的髓质  有狼性  -真神了
- It's like the medulla, the wolf brain. - Crazy, man.
-什么性  -原始的野性
- The what? - It's primitive stuff -- primitive stuff.
行  让我再嚎一次  再试一次
Okay, all right. Well, let me try it again. Let me try it again.
-够劲吧  -不错
- Yeah! Yeah? - Nice.
听听哥充满狼性的怒嚎
That's the wolf brain.
这鬼地方真无趣
Man! This town sucks!
哥们  抱歉在你地盘上大放厥词
Uh, sorry, bro. I know it's yours and everything.
但这才不到凌晨两点啊
But it's not even 2:00.
是啊  确实挺没劲
Yeah, it does kind of suck.
我知道一个...还没打烊的地儿
Hey, I know this, uh, after-hours place over --
在舍麦路附近
a couple blocks off Cermak.
-是吗  -想去不
- Yeah? - You want to hit it?
去  我们走
Hells yeah! Let's do it.
不醉不归
That's what I'm talking about.
一起来
Okay.
-别对着她耳朵就行  -没错
- Not in her ear. - All right.
-是吧  -不对着耳朵就行
- Right? - Not in her ear. Not in her ear.
对了  我还不知道你叫啥呢
Hey, uh, bro, I never did catch your name.
-我叫索尔  -索尔吗
- Saul. - Saul?
一切都好[索尔·古德曼同音]
S'all good, man.
懂没
Get it?
懂  好吧  索尔
I do. All right, Saul.
等等  哥们
Hey, hey, brother, whoa.
瞧瞧  这是啥
Check it out. What is that?
操
Holy shit.
这里至少有一千块呢
There's got to be at least a thousand bucks in here, man.
天  中大奖了
Oh, my god. Look at that.
-谁掉的啊  -我的啊
- Whose is it? - Mine.
占有即所有
不是说了占有即那啥...
Hey, possession's like 4/10ths of the --
行话怎么说的
What did you call it, bro?
里面有身份证啥的没
Like, is there an I.D. or...?
有
Yeah.
不认识  是个胖子
I don't know. Some fat guy.
估计是那个
I'm thinking that one.
我们...
Let's...
-天呐  -他是不...
- Jesus. - Is he, uh...
-什么  -他还活...
- What? - Is he, uh...
我咋知道
I don't know.
伙计  你还好吗
Hey, fella. You all right?
老兄
Hey, buddy.
你回个话行不
Hey, would you answer me?
回个毛  欠操
Hey. Answer this, you butthole.
什么  欠操
What? Butthole?
搞什么
What...the hell?
说话注意点
Hey, uh...hey, bro, be nice, all right?
他是想帮你呢
This guy right here is trying to help you.
帮个鬼  欠操
Help yourself to some of this, you butthole.
别一句一个欠操的
Hey. Hey, we're not buttholes, all right?
-闭嘴  -欠操  欠操
- So stop saying that. - Butt, butthole
-你是不有病啊  -欠欠操
- Hey, man, what's your problem? - Butt, butt
跟你们两个欠操的货叽歪才有病
My problem is I'm standing here talking to a couple buttholes.
你站个鬼  肥仔
Actually, you're not standing, you fat bastard.
肥臀垫地你没感觉吗
You're laying on your fat ass.
信不信哥一个回旋踢爆了你的头
Hey, I'll roundhouse-kick you right in your head.
信不信
And if you think I won't,
哥去你打工的麦当劳
I'll come to the McDonald's, where you work.
买下那...破地方
I'll buy... the whole damn place.
然后把你炒了
And I'll fire you.
跟你说  "拖把撂了  你被炒了"
I'll say, "Drop your mops, you buttholes, 'cause you're fired."
然后我再一个回旋踢
And then I'll roundhouse-kick you
正中你那猪头
right in your stupid heads.
尚格·云顿  好莱坞动作巨星  招牌动作360度回旋踢
剧中醉酒口误
之后哥再给你来个"约"格·云顿的招牌动作
Then I'll go "John"-Claude Van Damme on you...
你个欠操的
You butthole.
他的钱哥留下了
I'm keeping the money.
空钱包给你  肥子
Here you go, fatty.
手上那块表归我了
I got dibs on that watch, man.
让我看看
Let me see that.
什么牌子的
What kind is it?
不知道  就是块表
I don't know. It's just a watch.
我们走吧
We got to get out of here, man.
表什么牌子的
What kind of watch is it?
是...我也不知道
It's -- I don't know. It's...
让我看看
Well, then, let me look at it.
这可是块劳力士呢
It's a damn Rolex.
我又不懂
Oh. I don't know.
做人可不能这么黑心
Not cool to be greedy, bro.
-我先前不知道  -不厚道
- Uh, I don't -- I didn't know. - Not cool.
我不知道这是...
I di-- I didn't know what...
咱俩怎么分
So, how do you want to split this up?
这样吧  钱归你
I'll tell you what -- you keep the cash.
手表归我了
I'll just keep the watch.
可是  这表可值三千块  老兄
But the -- it's worth like 3 grand, man.
轻轻松松三千块
$3,000 easy.
-放屁  -真的
- No. - Yeah.
这样吧  我们先搞清楚再走
Come on, now. Let's figure this out. We got to get out of here.
好吧  依你
All right, yeah. You're right.
这样  我再给你加点钱
You know what? I...sweeten the pot.
我这有五  二十  四十  八十
I got, uh, $5, $20, $40, $60, $80
一共五百八十块
-- 580 bucks.
加上钱包里的一千块
Add that to the $1,000 --
可以买半块手表了
it's more than half.
那可说不准
What do you know about that thing?
这表应该不止三千块吧
I mean, is it worth more than $3,000?
我不知道  就这样了啊
No, I don't -- I don't know. But we're good, right?
-就这么定了  没意见吧  -好吧...
- Yeah? We good? Okay? - Well...
回见  二货
Later, sucker!
还剩六块
Six left.
还能再多搞几块吗
Can we get more?
但愿如此吧
God, I hope so.
来钱全不费功夫啊
It's like a license to print money.
绝对的美差
A thing of beauty.
你怎么想到回旋踢那一出的
Hey, what was that, uh, crazy stuff about roundhouse kicks?
哪来的灵感
Where the hell did you get that?
我不知道
I don't know, man.
这想法早就有了
Just something in my brain, you know?
就这样涌了出来  太过了吗
It just came out. Too much?
不  甚合我意
No. I loved it.
只是感觉略有深意
It was, like, deep or something.
论功绩的话
You want to talk about brilliant?
我们两个当中  你才是主力
I mean, we -- you're the man.
至于我  我喜欢欣赏你干活
Me -- I'm just -- I love watching you work, man.
也就赚点啤酒钱  仅此而已
It's good for making beer money -- that's about all.
绝命律师
第一季 第四集
拜托  没人会知道的
Please, okay? No one has to know.
你可以装作根本没找到我们
I mean, you could just pretend you didn't find us.
我们绝不告诉任何人  是吧克雷格
I -- we would never tell anyone, would we, Craig?
-对  绝对不说  -不会的
- No, absolutely not. - No.
我已经给你们的律师打过电话了
I already called your lawyer.
另外  你们一家这样一走
Besides, this little family outing of yours --
已经让一个无辜的人坐了牢
it's put an innocent man in jail.
警察正把这案子当作绑架案来调查
The cops are investigating this as a kidnapping.
他们已经抓到了一个倒霉的嫌疑人
They already rounded up some poor suspect.
工薪阶级  好像还是个父亲
A -- a-a working-class guy. Father...I think.
不管怎么说  你俩已经毁了某人的人生
But anyway, you two -- you almost ruined someone's life --
也许是很多人的人生
Potentially several someones.
我们真不知道这些
I -- we had no idea.
会不会是货车里那个人
Could this have been the person in the van?
如果他们抓到的人正好是警告里说的那人呢
What if the man they arrested is the one we were warned about?
这样看来  他可能也没那么无辜
Yeah, maybe he's not so innocent, hmm?
警告  怎么回事
Uh, warned? Warned how?
我们接到一个电话  有人用假嗓音打的
Well, we had a phone call -- someone disguising their voice.
他们说有人要找我们麻烦
Yeah, they said someone was coming for us.
我家外面还停着一辆货车
And there was a van outside the house... yep.
好像有人在车里监视着我们
...as if whoever was inside was watching us.
所以  车一开走
And, uh, once that drove off,
-我们为了孩子就这样做了  -为了孩子
- We...did what we did for the kids. - The kids.
我不知道有这回事
I-I-I wouldn't know about any of that.
我只是...
I just...
我可以向你们保证  你和家人很安全
I can assure you that you and your family are safe.
现在警察已经全权介入  所以
I mean, the police are all over this thing, so...
不是这个问题  我们不能就这么回去
It -- it doesn't matter. Uh, we can't just go back.
是案子的问题  他们不会放过克雷格的
I mean, it's -- our case. They'll crucify Craig.
你能再给韦克斯勒小姐打个电话吗
Can't you just call Ms. Wexler again?
就说你其实根本没看到我们
You know, tell her you didn't see us after all.
如果他们认为我是逃跑的
If they think I ran away,
肯定会怀疑我
it'll look like I did something wrong.
我们不能冒风险
Yeah, and we can't risk losing everything
因为一点小错误就失去一切
just because of some teensy mistake.
-这真的...  -我能问你们点事吗
- I mean, it's... - Can I ask you something?
你们本来是怎么希望的
What -- what were you hoping would happen?
在我找到你们之前  你们有什么打算
I mean, before I found you, what were you planning to do?
我们还在...考虑
Well, we were in the process of, you know, working that out...
-还在考虑...  -然后你就...
- We were working that out. -...When you, um... we were--
好吧
All right, well, uh,
天无绝人之路
you still got a little bit of maneuverability, all right?
你们爱好野外活动  对吧
You -- you're outdoorsy, right?
所以你们就来了一场说走就走的野营
So you went on an impromptu camping trip.
人有时候就是这么任性
I don't know. It's something people do, apparently.
你们把家里搞得一团乱
Uh, you left the house a mess,
把自家前门踹开
and you kicked in your own front door
因为这是个自由国度
because it's a free country.
金·韦克斯勒很厉害  她能让人信服
Kim Wexler is very good. She'll make it work.
那  钱怎么办
Yeah, what -- what about the money?
如果她知道了钱的事  她一定会上报吧
Uh, well, if she knows about it, she'll tell, right?
我是说她不得不上报吧
I mean, she'll have to tell.
就像硅谷人说的那样
Well, like they say in Silicon Valley,
"那不是故障  是产品特色"
"It's not a bug -- it's a feature."
听说过可以放弃的谈判筹码吗
Did you ever hear of a bargaining chip?
我们面前的这一堆
Well, what we have right here
就是可放弃的筹码
is the mother of all bargaining chips.
你是想让我们把钱上交
Um, as in...you expect us to give this back?
我们不会把钱交回去的
We are not giving this back.
我们没有罪  这钱是我们应得的
Uh, we are not guilty. This money belongs to us.
是我们  是克雷格赚到的
We ea-- well, I mean, Craig earned it.
我很努力地工作
I worked very hard...
我周末  节假日都在工作
...You know, weekends and holidays...
-总是白做工  -白做工  一直都是
- ...All unpaid. - All unpaid, always.
虽然给我们发了工资
And -- and, really, just because you're salaried
那也不能不给加班费啊
doesn't mean you don't deserve overtime.
我觉得这样才公平
I-I think that's only fair.
没错  就是这个问题
I mean, really, that's what this is about, right?
-事关公平二字  -没错  公平
- Yeah. Fairness. - Fairness, right.
这不光是合不合法的问题
I mean, not just what's legal.
要说合法  你看奴隶制
If you want to talk about legal, slavery --
以前蓄奴还合法呢
that used to be legal -- human slavery, so...
是这么回事哈
Yeah, this is right up there with that.
求你了  别告诉任何人这笔钱的事
Please, just don't tell anyone about the money.
-我不能受贿  -谁知道啊
- I can't take a bribe. - Who would know?
-我们对谁也不说  -是啊  拿着吧
- We won't tell anyone. - Yeah, take it.
那也不行
I can't take it.
拿着吧  你刚才不是说想帮我们吗
Please. Didn't you say that you wanted to help us?
你就假装从没见过这钱  这不难吧
So just pretend you never saw the money. How hard is that?
快拿着
Take it.
拿着啊
我...我真的不能拿
I can't -- I can't take a bribe.
不过
But you know what?
我可以把它当预付金
I can-- I can take a retainer.
预付金
A retainer?
对  我当你们的律师  你们给我预付金啊
Yeah, for my services -- as your lawyer?
-你并不是我们的律师  -现在还不是而已
- You're not our lawyer. - Well, not yet.
我知道  哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所光鲜亮丽
Look...I know that HHM is shiny and it's slick
里面的律师一抓一大把
and it's chock-full of lawyers
和他们相比  我就像个
and, compared to them, I'm like a --
卖柠檬水的小摊  企图和沃尔玛竞争
a kiddy lemonade stand trying to compete with Wal-mart.
但是  我能为你们提供的服务
But here's the thing -- what are you gonna get from me
别人都无法提供
that you're not gonna get from those other guys?
比如我的热情与专注
Passion, commitment.
你们自己想想看  是谁找到你们的
Ask yourself this -- who found you?
我可没看到霍华德·哈姆林
I don't see Howard Hamlin
穿着他三百块的古驰皮鞋来这儿找你们
ruining his $300 Gucci loafers out here.
如果请我  那二位就是我的头号委托人
If you're with me, you're my number-one client.
不管早中晚给我打电话  我随时待命
Morning, noon, or night, you call me -- I'm there.
我将会全心全意为你们服务
I would be singularly devoted to you.
不行吗  为什么
But why not?
对不起
I'm sorry.
因为你...
You're just...the...
我怎么了
Just...I'm what?
有罪的人才找你当律师
You're the kind of lawyer guilty people hire.
上报纸了吗
Did it make the paper?
什么
What?
那案子上报纸了吗
Did it make the paper?
什么案子上报纸
Did what make the paper?
好吧  看来是错过截稿期了
Okay, well, probably missed the deadline,
你明早再看  肯定在头版头条
But check it out tomorrow morning -- front page.
凯特尔曼一家四口
The Kettlemans, all four of them --
安然无恙
Safe and sound.
-都让你说中了  -嗯
- Looks like you called it. - Yeah.
他们当时在野营  就在他家后院里
Camping -- you know, pretty much right in their own backyard --
不对  离他家后院还有五英里
Well 5 miles above it.
我的天
Jesus.
那晚真糟糕  我鞋里都是松子
The night I had. I got pine nuts in my shoes.
我是说  这事也太难以置信了
But, I mean, can you believe it?
好吧  你肯定不觉得奇怪
I-I guess you can.
我就是觉得吧
It's just, you know,
本以为罪犯要比他们看起来聪明得多
you assume that criminals are gonna be smarter than they are.
我真搞不懂
I don't know.
这事还真让我小难过了一把
It kind of breaks my heart a little.
看你不怎么爱说话啊
Not the loquacious sort, are you?
不是所有人都像你巧舌如簧
We can't all be as blessed as you.
多谢你那天帮我
Well, thanks for your help.
没什么
Don't mention it.
那个  你要是需要帮忙的话...
And, uh, if you ever need any assistance...
禁止吸烟
怎么把我的委托人给铐上了
Why is my client in handcuffs?
他是无辜的  是受害人
This man is innocent. He's a victim.
他怎么能戴手铐呢
Why -- why on earth would he be cuffed?
快把手铐摘下来  这下好了
Just go -- go ahead. Take them off. There you go.
你自由了
Free at last!
他告诉你那个好消息了吗
Hey, did he tell you the good news?
根本不是什么绑架  怎么样
Never even kidnapped -- how about that?
全城不戒备一下
A family can't go on a little vacation
人家都不能去野营了是吧
without the whole city going on lockdown?
对了  你那搭档在哪
By the way, where is your partner?
你俩扔硬币你输了是吧
What -- did you lose the coin toss?
我们要他来道歉  你也得道歉
Because we expect an apology from him, as well as you.
你个傻逼  少在这儿得寸进尺
You really don't want to push your luck with me, scumbag.
还有你这混蛋  我们可盯着你呢
You got eyes on you, asshole.
你要再敢犯事  就等着瞧吧
One little slip -- just one.
好好好  你们牛气  行了吧
Yeah, well, you're -- you're both very pretty, so...
那个...
Well...
你让我做的我做了  没让的我也做了
I believe I did more than what you asked of me,
咱俩这下互不相欠了吧
So, uh, that would make us square, yes?
那就好
Great.
要不要我搭你一程
You need a ride?
野营
Camping?
你觉得我会信这种鬼话吗
You expect me to believe that shit?
我知道你不信
Yeah, I know it.
可是人们有时是这样
The things people do, huh?
我前脚和你说好那事
They decide to go camping
他们后脚就跑出去野营
right after I run my little offer by you?
生活本来就充满了巧合啊
Could be argued that all of life is one great coincidence.
一定是有人让他们去"野营"
Somebody told those people to, um, go camping.
那人给他们提了个醒
Somebody warned them.
他们本来就爱往林子里钻
They're very woodsy.
而且说实话
And between you and me,
他们属于做决定十分冲动的人
they're pretty rash when it comes to the decision-making.
并不是真正懂得深谋远虑的人
I mean, they're not really the plan-ahead types.
如果我是你  就赶紧把那油腔滑调
Yeah, I'd cut the cute attitude right about now
收起来
if I were you.
你出卖了我  是会付出代价的
You ratted on me. There will be consequences.
如果有人警告了凯特尔曼一家
Hey, if somebody warned the Kettlemans,
那也是因为担心那两个孩子
it was probably somebody who was worried about those kids.
你知道你给我惹了多大的麻烦吗
You know how much trouble you caused me?
你被抓住可不是我害得
You didn't need any help getting caught, okay?
邻居认出了你  是你大意了
The neighbor ID'd you. You were sloppy.
不管惹了多大麻烦  都是你自找的
Any trouble you might have -- that's on you.
更别提你车里的血迹了
Not to mention the blood in your van.
你就不能用点清洁剂吗
Here's a thought -- Ajax, Formula 409!
你根本不知道为了让你出来
You have no idea the tap-dance I had
我跟那些警察兜了多少圈子
to give those cops to get you out of here.
是你给他们拱手奉上一大堆疑点
You gave them probable cause out the wazoo.
即使真的有人
Now, and whoever the somebody is
警告了凯特尔曼一家  让他们离开
who may have warned the Kettlemans got them out of there
你才因此没有做出更蠢的事
before you did anything even more stupid.
那你也应该感谢那个好心人
You should be thanking this good samaritan.
因为不管那人是谁  他帮了你的忙
Because whoever he is, he did you a favor.
日间美容美甲
我们来按小时计费
Okay, um, I'm thinking hourly here.
由于出现了一些特殊情况
There were some special circumstances,
所以我们的贵宾价
so our elite-tier pricing
为每小时九百五十美元
would be...$950 an hour.
总计二十个小时
Round it off to 20 hours.
一万九千美元
$19,000...
再加上一千美元差旅费
Plus $1,000 for travel expenses.
咨询费一千五百美元
Consulting fees -- $1,500.
调研费用
And, uh, research...
立案费五千
Five for filing fees.
外出餐补
I ate on the road.
还有保管费
And storage fees.
各种杂费
Miscellaneous expenses.
我要把我的教会建造在这磐石上
Upon this rock, I will build my church.
马太福音16:18
要双排扣还是单排  先生
Double-breasted or single, sir?
单排  我希望你把袖孔开高一些
Single. Now, I want you to cut the armholes high, okay?
-当然  -还有中间要修身一些  修身型
- Of course. - And, uh, trim through the middle -- trim.
要什么布料的
Cloth?
羊毛
Uh, oh, well, uh, wool.
对了
Yeah. Uh...
"特级170塔斯马尼亚羊毛"
"Super 170 Tasmanian wool."
-很好的选择  先生  -谢谢
- Beautiful choice, sir. - Thanks.
海军蓝  好吗
Navy, all right?
就是它  非常好  细条纹的
Oh, that's it. Perfect. Pinstripe.
是不是该讨论衬衫了
Shall we discuss shirts?
好  我要你们这里最好的海岛棉面料
Okay, I'm gonna need your finest sea island cotton
白色圆角领和翻边袖口
with a white club collar and french cuffs.
我这里正好有
I have the very thing.
我认为你还想看看领带吧
And I'm assuming you want to see some ties?
对  我预想差不多应该是
Yeah, I was, you know, picturing something in a --
浅蓝色的针织领带
a light-blue knit.
还有请确保
Oh, and, uh, could you make sure
衬衫上是真正的珍珠母纽扣  好吗
those are real mother-of-pearl buttons on the shirts, okay?
不要那些假的塑料玩意
None of this fake plastic crap.
当然  我马上回来
Of course. I'll be right back.
给这位先生倒杯咖啡  大卫
Some coffee, David, for the gentleman?
找到了
Here we are.
要试试吗
Shall we?
好  来吧
Yeah, let's go.
你怎么想
So, um, what do you think?
披头士的一首歌  以梦幻感闻名
-"永远的草莓地"色吗  -对
- "Strawberry fields forever"? - Mm.
绚丽色彩
不对  你疯了吗
No. Are you crazy?
-边都沾不上  -是一样的
- N-not even close. - Yes, it is.
-看啊  -不不
- Look. - No, no.
"闪亮黄樟色"更像  像多了
It's way more "Sassafras glow" -- way more.
好好看看  就是"永远的草莓地"色
Use your eyes -- Strawberry Fields Forever.
女士们  帮我看看  这是"闪亮黄樟色"
Ladies, back me up. Hey. Is it -- sassafras glow.
-我对吗  -对  不对
- Am I right?  -Yeah. No.
或者"金色狂想曲"  不过  看到了吗
Maybe "Rhapsody in blonde," but...yeah, see?
她们同意我说的
They agree with me.
人们不是常说"顾客永远是对的"吗
Whatever happened to "The customer is always right"?
闪亮黄樟色  去配吧  好吗
Sassafras glow -- mix it up, all right?
你错了  你会看到的
You're wrong. You'll see.
那有什么关系  大不了我明早洗掉
Big deal. I'll wash it out in the morning.
-多大点事啊  -这是漂发
- No biggie. Geez. - It's bleach.
-洗不掉的  -什么
- It doesn't wash out. - What?
是永久性的吗
It's permanent?
那我们还是直接修图吧
We'll photoshop the color, okay?
计划有变  女士们
Change of plan, ladies.
我只要做简单的烫卷
I want to go with a simple curling-iron job, okay?
给我做那种小卷发
Uh, give me, like, ringlets --
1960年版的《斯巴达克斯》
就像《斯巴达克斯》里面托尼·柯蒂斯那种
You know, on top, like Tony Curtis in "Spartacus."
对  就像《斯巴达克斯》里浴室那场戏那样
Yeah, like the bath scene in "Spartacus."
对  那个"我是斯巴达克斯"
Okay. "I am Spartacus."
别再议论了
Stop talking about it!
快让我变漂亮
Make me beautiful, already.
喂
Hello.
这里是詹姆斯·M·麦吉尔先生的律所
You've reached the law offices of James M. McGill, esquire,
一位值得你信赖的律师
a lawyer you can trust.
请在响声后留下你的信息
Kindly leave your information at the tone,
麦吉尔先生会尽快给你回电
and Mr. McGill will phone you promptly.
是我
Hey. Uh...it's me.
《怪形》这周六上映
Anyway, uh, "The Thing" is playing downtown on Saturday.
我觉着你应该会喜欢库特·拉塞尔的表演
Thought you might be up for some Kurt Russell action.
我欠你个人情  那要不先吃晚饭
I owe you one, so why don't we just grab some dinner first?
我请
My treat.
要是...你不想来的话
And...uh, you know, if not,
也给我回个电话好吗
can you give me a call anyway?
我真的很想跟你谈谈
I really want to talk to you.
就这样  再见
Okay. Uh, bye.
请进
Come in.
事情怎么样了
How goes it?
有点棘手
Tricky, for sure.
克雷格和贝茜让我们在警察面前的处境很不妙
Craig and Betsy really put us in a corner with the police,
更不用说媒体方面了
Not to mention the press.
但是  他们的野营一说
But this camping story of theirs --
倒是编的无懈可击
they've been keeping it consistent, at least.
如果你同意的话
If it's okay with you,
我觉得应该劝他们雇一家公关公司
I think I should try to talk them into hiring a P.R. Firm --
应付接下来的几周
certainly for the next couple of weeks.
所以  你同意吗
So, okay on the P.R. Firm?
-你现在有空吗  -当然有
- Do you have a minute? - Yeah, of course.
有什么事吗
What's up?
跟我出去兜个风
Take a ride with me.
好的  可是  去哪里兜
Uh, okay. Uh... where are we going?
操
Shit.
是啊
Yep.
他穿的是...我的西装  对吧
That's...I mean, that's my suit, right?
是我疯了吗
Am I crazy here?
詹姆斯·M·麦吉尔  律师
你没疯
No, you're not crazy.
你看那个标志  那是我们的商标
Look at the logo. That's our logo.
他根本就是在抄袭我们
He's just straight-up copying us.
他脑子里到底在想什么啊
I mean, what the hell is he thinking with this?
我真的  他...他行事不羁
I really -- h-h-he's, you know, a free spirit.
说的也是
Yeah, that's one way to put it.
你俩还是朋友对吧
You two are still friends, right?
-关系不是很  -但还是能说上话的
- I wouldn't exactly -- - You talk, though.
不...怎么说
Not...really --
但他找到凯特尔曼一家
Still, you're the one he called
在桑迪亚斯露营的时候  他打电话给你了
when he found the Kettlemans camped halfway up the Sandias.
他只是想为自己的委托人开脱罢了
He was just looking out for his own client -- that's all.
金  我不是严刑逼供你
This isn't the Third Degree, Kim.
我...我不在乎你们俩关系好不好
I-I really don't care one way or the other.
我只是...
I just...
他这么做太狠了
He's really forcing my hand here.
我打扰到你了吗
Am I interrupting?
没有  来得正好  来来
Not at all. Perfect timing. Come on.
请坐
Sit.
做个按摩吧  免费的
Have a massage, free of charge.
-好啊  -这个足浴也要体验一下
- Okay. - Got to try the foot bath, too.
这把老骨头终于可以歇歇了
Give the old dogs a rest.
要调到深度按摩模式  不然的话
A-and go for the deep-tissue setting. Otherwise --
是这个小的吗
Is that the small fist?
你得用那个  三个箭头那档
Use the -- it's three arrows.
-是啊  我按了那个  -就  对了
- I did. I pressed it. - Just -- yeah.
你现在感觉到了吗  好吧
Now you feel it? Good.
-现在放松试试  -好的
- Now relax, okay? - Okay.
你得休息一下犒劳自己
You deserve a break today.
-真的很舒服  -我早说过了
- It's very nice. - Told you.
我每晚都能免费享受
I get this free every night --
这就是住在美容院里的好处之一
Just one of the perks of salon living.
-其他好处是  -你看  有免费黄瓜水喝
- The others being... - Free cucumber water, obviously.
当然  有免费的修甲吗
Obviously. Free mani-pedis?
修甲享超低折扣
Deep discount mani-pedis.
毕竟人家还是要吃饭的
Because the ladies still got to eat, you know?
好吧  那还是不错的
Well, it's still a deal.
看来你活得很滋润啊
Living like a king, then.
这是什么  是禁止令吗
What's this? Is this a cease and desist?
-是的  -好吧
- Yeah. - Yeah.
他有多生气
How pissed was he?
至少头没气炸
Well, his head didn't actually explode,
但是  还是气得够呛
But, you know, pretty damn pissed...
直骂"你肯定没好下场"这种
...like "This won't end well for you" pissed.
-那又如何  -吉米
- How about that? - Jimmy.
-这不是闹着玩的  -我知道
- This is serious. - I know.
-你真的知道吗  -当然
- Do you?  I mean, - Yeah.
那块广告板到底是怎么回事啊
what the hell is with that billboard?
我知道你跟哈姆林过不去  但我
I know you have a problem with Hamlin, but I
我不懂你那是什么意思
I just don't get your angle here.
你不是要建自己的律所吗
Aren't you trying to build your own law practice?
但你现在花了一大笔钱
Instead, you're spending god knows how much money
把自己变成了哈姆林翻版
turning yourself into a little Hamlin clone.
你干嘛要针对他
I mean...why are you making this personal?
-没有针对他  -明明就是
- It's not personal. - It is so personal.
这完完全全就是针对他
It is completely and totally personal.
-不  都说了不是了  -是  明明就是
- No, no, no. It's not. No. - Yes. Yes, it is.
别再装了
Stop trying to pretend.
我就不能做广告了吗
I can advertise, can't I?
什么  难道我做什么事都要
What, do I have to clear everything
-经过万能的霍华德同意吗  -对
- Past the great and powerful Howard? - Yes,
你可以做广告  吉米  随你
you can advertise, Jimmy, all you want.
但那广告牌不是广告宣传
That billboard is not advertising.
那是宣战
That is a declaration of war.
宣战  那...
Declaration of war? That's...
它就在哈姆林出口
It's right at Hamlin's exit.
你知道他每天都开车从那过
You know he drives by it every day.
那是生意  我在创建一个品牌
It's business. I'm building a brand.
你是剽窃别人的品牌
You're ripping off a brand.
那个广告里一点原创的东西也没有
There is nothing original in that ad.
它绝对代表不了吉米·麦吉尔
It certainly doesn't represent Jimmy McGill.
你听好了  是他打响了第一枪
Hey, all right, now, he fired the first shot, okay?
不许我用我自己的名字  金
Trying to keep me from using my name, my own name, Kim?
我理解
I get that.
但  你可以做得更好
But this... you're better than this.
-我可以做得更好  -对
- I'm better than this? - Yeah.
- I'm better than this? - Yes.
-我更好  -对
- I'm better? - You are.
你比那个蠢哈姆林强
Well, you're better than that schmuck Hamlin!
-拜托  吉米  -你...
- Oh, come on, Jimmy. - You -- hey.
-拜托  -你可以在任何地方工作
- Come on. - You could work anywhere.
你可以在欣赏你的公司工作
You could be somewhere where they appreciate you --
在能看到你价值的公司工作
You know, where they see how valuable you are,
他们会关心你
Where -- I don't know -- maybe they care about you?!
别想了  好吗
Forget it, okay?
如果哈姆林要对付我
If Hamlin wants to come after me,
他知道我在哪
he knows where I am.
我会准备好  全副武装
I'll be ready, guns blazing.
禁止令只是个开始
The cease and desist is just the beginning.
下一步就是强制令
The next step is an injunction.
这场战争你是赢不了的
You can't win this fight.
法官大人  我是卑微的个体律师
Your honor, I'm a humble solo practitioner,
只想在这个充满竞争
merely trying to ply my trade
且日新月异的市场里有一席之地
in an aggressive and evolving marketplace.
正如我不断重申的  这是商标侵权
As I've argued repeatedly, this is trademark infringement.
麦吉尔先生的新商标完全是抄我们的
Mr. McGill's new logo is an absolute copy of ours.
我认为这是合理使用
I think it falls firmly under fair use.
合理使用
Fair use?
你明显从中获利  这不是合理使用
You're clearly profiting, so fair use doesn't apply.
字体就那么几种
It -- there are only so many fonts out there.
难道都属于哈姆林先生吗
Does Mr. Hamlin outright own them all?
不  但我们用这种字体
No, but we've been using this particular font
已经十二年了
for 12 years now, and it,
还有我们的三矩形图案
in concert with our tri-rectangle graphic
和哈姆林靛蓝  共同组成了注册商标
and hamlindigo blue, constitutes a trademarked brand identifier.
等等  你说啥
Whoa, whoa. Back up.
哈姆林靛蓝
Hamlindigo blue?
对
Yes.
那是我们注册的名字
That is our trademarked name.
天啊
Holy crap.
你真的管一个颜色叫"哈姆林靛蓝"
You seriously named a color "Hamlindigo"?
真是  哇
That is -- yikes.
"哇"  从一个穿着和我一样的人嘴里冒出来
"Yikes"? From the man dressed exactly like me.
法官大人  我感觉
Your honor, I feel like
我在和格劳乔·马克思做镜子表演
I'm in the mirror routine with Groucho Marx,
美国喜剧演员
我们应该站着  向对方挥手
like we should be standing, waving our arms at each other.
真的吗  我可看不出来
Really? I don't see it.
另外  出现在两个商标上的名字麦吉尔
In addition, the name McGill appears in both logos,
我认为  麦吉尔先生是想
which, I believe, Mr. McGill is hoping
让潜在客户更加迷惑
to further confuse potential clients.
所以我连自己的名字都不能用吗
So I can't advertise under my own name now?
就因为恰巧和他们律所的一个合伙人
I'm to be penalized 'cause I happen to
名字相同  就要被处罚吗
share a name with one of HHM's partners?
你不能不让我用自己的名字
You can't take my name from me.
名字不是现在的问题  麦吉尔先生
The name is not the problem here, Mr. McGill.
哈姆林先生显然认为是问题
Uh, Mr. Hamlin certainly seems to think so.
他想让我改名  因为他声称
I mean, he wants me to change my name 'cause he claims that --
这对他的事业造成了一些威胁
that -- what -- it's some kind of threat to his business?
法官大人  这是贸易管制
Your honor. This is restraint of trade, okay?
现在不是自由市场吗
Whatever happened to the free market, huh?
不  哈姆林是想告诉你...
No, Hamlin here wants you to tell --
好  够了  麦吉尔先生  我听够了
Okay, Okay, I've —- enough. Mr. McGill, I've heard enough.
好  你有权利
All right, yes, you are within your rights
用你自己名字做广告
to advertise using your own name.
但是  根据我的判断  这个广告牌明显
However, in my estimation, the billboard clearly
有意抄袭了
and intentionally duplicates elements
哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所的商标
of the Hamlin Hamlin & McGill logo.
你是主动抄袭他们已成立的品牌
You're actively copying their established brand
谋求个人利益
for your own gain.
我不认为还有其他合理解释
I don't see any other reasonable explanation.
-法官大人  我...  -吉米  吉米
- Your honor, I -- - Jimmy, Jimmy.
放聪明点
Wise up.
这个广告牌必须在四十八小时内拆除
The billboard must come down within 48 hours.
这就是经典的弱者对巨人的故事
This is a classic David vs. Goliath story.
他凭借自己庞大的律所
I mean, you got your gigantic law firm
践踏所有小公司
stomping all over the little guy.
对  但这都可以算做黑幕报道了
Yeah, but it's investigative journalism at its best.
这正是你的拿手好戏
I-it's right up your alley. Uh-huh.
好吧  我把我的号码给你  如果...
Yeah, o-okay, well, let me give you my cell just in case...
好  谢谢
Uh -- yeah. Thank you.
请接新闻采编部
Can I get the news desk, please?
我有个大爆料
I got a hot tip.
你难道不想成为搞倒大律所的电视台吗
Don't you want to be the station that brought down big law?
你可以像那些搞倒大烟草公司的记者一样
You could be like the reporters that brought down big tobacco.
就像伍德沃德和伯恩斯坦揭露水门事件那样
Look, I'm talking Woodward and Bernstein here.
你关于自动取款机乱收费的曝光  非常棒
Hey, your exposé on predatory ATM fees -- that was... wow!
这是误判
Well, it's a miscarriage of justice,
我觉得你们的读者会非常乐意
and I think your viewers would be very, very interested
并感激你曝光这种不公正行为
and, uh, grateful to you for exposing this injustice.
我觉得这没危及到社区健康
I wouldn't characterize this as a community health risk,
但肯定跟社区利益有关
but it's definitely in the community interest.
不  没错
No, yes,
哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所是社区支柱
HHM is a pillar of the community, yes.
不  斗争也是很重要的故事
No, I -- the war is an important story, as well.
所以这种行为很过分
That's why this action is so egregious.
当然  行
Sure. Okay.
至少要报导地有点人情味
Well, at least consider the human-interest angle here.
你在逗我吗
Are you kidding?
律师自己白手起家
It's -- lawyer pulls himself up by his bootstraps,
结果被家族大律所踩在脚下
only to be ground under the heel of the old-money megafirm?
那是《心灵与智慧》的情节  喂
That's Hearts and Minds! You -- hello?
是  我也有你的号码
Yeah, I have your number, too, so...
我懂了
Yeah, I see.
新墨西哥大学
行
Okay.
新墨西哥大学  媒体实验室
别  别  别碰  伙计
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, man.
什么都别碰
Can't touch the goods.
我填了表  只有我能碰摄像机
I signed the form -- only I can touch the camera.
行  我建议你扩大画面
Fine, may I suggest you widen the frame to include --
广告牌才是故事主角
The billboard is the story, okay?
我也是故事主角  我也得在里面
No, I'm also the story, so...got to get me in there.
站在标记上
Okay, so, get on your mark.
我对你捉襟见肘的摄影经验没意见
You know, uh, no offense to your minutes of experience,
但开始之前我还是得看看
but I'd like to see what we got before we do this, okay?
那家伙
Other guy.
说的就是你  站在我刚站的地方
Only other guy that's here, go stand where I was standing.
蹲一点  蹲一点
Uh...shrink down. Shrink down.
矮一点  好了
You know, scrunch. Yeah.
扩大画面  把广告牌拍进来
Okay, widen the frame. Get the billboard.
好  然后拍我  我  我
Okay, now get me. Me, me, me, me, me.
不是我  拍他  他就是我  就这样
No. Not me -- get him. He's me. Yeah, like that.
-明白吗  -明白
- Got it? - Yeah.
很好
Good.
好  他在镜头里吗
Okay. Is he in the shot?
没有  开始吧
No. Dude, just go.
-我怎么样  -很好看
- How do I look? - Great.
我  不  我这边比较好看
I'll, uh -- no, this is my good side.
-广告牌拍进来了吗  -是的
- Is, uh -- is the billboard in? - Yes!
你说一百美元一小时  不是他妈的三小时
Jesus, just -- you said $100 for one hour, not fricking 3.
你明显有记者的冲动
You clearly have a journalistic impulse.
你真积极  你知道吗
You're a real go-getter, you know that?
快拍
Go get this.
好  我倒数
All right, count me down.
五  四  三
In 5, 4, 3...
要严肃
Gravitas.
我是詹姆斯·麦吉尔
I'm James McGill.
和许多美国人一样  我自力更生
Like most Americans, I'm a self-made man.
通过自己努力从法律学校毕业
I put myself through law school.
在法庭当公设辩护律师
Working in the courts as a public defender,
我代理过很多无路可走的人
I represented those with nowhere else to turn.
我相信司法体系  这是我事业的基础
I believe in service. It's what I've built my career on.
但我也有梦想  很多人共有的梦想
But I've also had a dream, a dream that many of us have --
自己创业的梦想
a dream to own my own business.
我精打细算  省吃俭用  终于
Well, I-I scrimped and I saved, and finally,
我买得起那个广告位了
I was able to buy one billboard...
能给我刚开的律所打个小广告
...A tiny foray into advertising for my fledgling law firm.
大家总说
I've always been told
美国遍地是机会
that America is the land of opportunity,
直到今天我还深信不疑
and I believed it...until today.
但广告牌竖起来还不到二十四小时
Not 24 hours after my billboard went up,
一家大公司就对我穷追不舍
a large law firm came after me.
他们说我损害了他们的生意
They said that I was hurting their business.
他们有钱有势  但我只是一个普通人
They're rich. They're powerful. I'm just...one man.
你觉得法庭会站在谁那边
So, who do you think the courts sided with?
现在我的广告位倒下了
So now my little billboard comes down.
我告诉你
Let me tell you something --
如果他们想斗  那我们就斗到底
if they want a fight, they're gonna get a fight,
因为我不会放弃
because I'm not giving up, not --
我的天  你看那人
Holy shit! Dude, the dude!
-救命  -你看那人
- Help! - Dude, the dude!
你看那个工人
The w-- the worker guy!
我的天
Holy shit.
来人啊  救我下去
Please! Aah! Get me down!
-你看那人  -行  快报警
- Dude! - Yeah, okay, call 911!
-救救我  -你有手机吗
- Help me! Aah! - You got a cell?
-有  -救命啊
- Yeah, yeah. - Aah! Please!
有人快要从山南边临街的
Yeah, a guy just fell off a billboard
广告牌上摔下来了
from frontage road south of mountain.
伙计
Hey, man!
救救我
Help me!
我觉得那样不安全
Hey, man, I don't think that's very safe!
你得有执照才能上去吧
You need to be, like, licensed for that!
-救救我  -天
- Help me! - Man.
别往下看
Not looking down.
一次一级
One rung at a time.
别往下
Not looking down.
快点
Hurry up!
快来救我
Come get me!
救命
Help!
救救我
Help me! Aah!
-先生  我就在这里  -救我
- Sir, I'm right here! - Please!
求求你
Please!
-拉我上去  -抓住我的手
- Pull me up! - Here, grab my hand!
拉我上去
Pull me up!
-拉我上去  -抓住
- Pull me up! - Here!
你没事吧
You okay?
动作怎么那么慢
Took you long enough.
解救工人
本地英雄律师
是  我当时吓死了
I was scared, yes.
其实我还是
I mean, I'm not really a big fan of heights --
有点恐高
Let me tell you.
但我内心有个声音说  "必须救人"
But, you know, something inside me said, "You have to do this."
我觉得就算没有我
I'm sure our city's first responders
急救人员也会及时到场
would have been here momentarily.
天啊  你相信这家伙吗
Oh, jesus, can you believe this guy?
但至少我的出现让大家安了心
But at least I was able to provide a reassuring presence.
这简直就是在做秀  肯定是这样
This whole thing was a publicity stunt. It's got to be.
我觉得一人有难时
I think that's kind of all anybody wants
都希望别人伸出援手
when they're in trouble.
当然  我不认为人生...
You know, of course, I didn't think that life...
不会有人信吧
You don't think anyone's gonna actually buy this?
...会在生命攸关之时
...was gonna call on me in such an immediate
-向我求助  -很难说  人们喜欢英雄
- And, life-threatening way. - It's hard to say. People love a hero.
...都会毫不犹豫  是吧
...take it as it comes, right?
我身处当时那种情况
The universe put me in that spot at that moment.
怎么会拒绝
Who am I to say no?
作为一名律师  我每天都在帮助他人
You know, as a lawyer, while I help people every day,
可能不受这么多关注
I may not get as much attention for it.
这就是做秀
Whole thing's a damn stunt.
但我觉得我的委托人
But I think my clients know
都知道他们有难  我都会帮忙
that when they're in trouble, I'm there.
我只是在对的时间...
I was just a guy who was in the right...
您有七条留言
You have seven new messages.
听留言请按一
To listen to your messages, press "1."
第一条  五点四十分收到
First message, received at 5:40...
本地律师  本地英雄
这都靠演技  查克
It's just showmanship, Chuck.
没错  是的
Yeah, right.
你今天很早
You're early.
你有没有
Did you --
是  我放电了  今天很棒
Yeah, I grounded myself. Hey, big day.
我电话响个不停
My phone's ringing off the hook.
上午有三个咨询  三个哦
I have three consults before lunchtime -- three.
太棒了  吉米
That's great, Jimmy.
咸鱼翻身了
Yep. The worm has turned.
真的很不错
Oh. That's really great.
你觉得突然改善的原因是什么
So, to what do you credit this sudden change?
我承认  你说得对
Well, I got to admit -- you were right.
为什么
How so?
你叫我继续努力
Well, you told me to keep plugging
干好活儿  委托人不请自来
and, uh, you know, do good work, and the clients will come.
我承认
You know, I'll -- I'll admit,
我有几次差点丢失信念  但我咸鱼翻身了
I almost lost faith a couple times, but the worm has turned.
你公设案的委托人
So, uh, what -- you've been getting referrals
给你推荐客户了吗
from your P.D. clients?
没错
Uh, yeah.
工作努力  向别人证明你脑子还不错
You know, you work hard, show you got half a brain,
人们就会像你说的那样上门
and people come knocking, like you said.
我现在只需做好宣传
I just needed to get my face out there.
检察官有推荐委托人吗
So, prosecutors, then -- referring clients?
当然有
Yeah. Yep. Exactly.
是伯杰龙吗
Was it Bergeron?
我刚起步时  她把我推荐给几个好客户
When I was starting out, she sent me a couple good ones.
没错  其实
Yeah, uh, it was --
是她一个手下推荐的
It was someone on her team you know?
肯吃苦耐劳  不要不三不四
I mean, hey, just took some elbow grease and clean living --
人们就会注意你
People noticed.
我就知道你有潜力
I knew you had it in you.
今天的报纸呢
I don't see the journal here.
对
Right.
-在这里  -不  不
- Here you go. - No, no, no.
《阿尔布开克日报》不见了
Uh, Albuquerque Journal -- it's not here.
外面我也没看到
Oh, yeah. I didn't see it outside.
没在外面吗
Wasn't out there?
-总在外面啊  -我没看到
- It's always out there. - I didn't see it.
可能忘记投递了
Maybe they forgot to deliver it.
可能有小孩拿走了
Maybe some kids grabbed it.
那个小孩肯定非常喜欢
Because if there's one thing kids love,
本地的报纸
it's local print journalism.
我不知道怎么说
I don't know what to tell you.
但你有一堆可以读的东西
You got a ton of reading material there.
你看  《金融时报》
Look, hey. Financial Times.
我知道阿尔布开克是国际事务的中心
You know, I know Albuquerque is a hub of global intrigue,
-但这个应该够你读了吧  -好吧  行
- but you think that'll tide you over? - All right, fine.
但如果明天还没有
But if it's not here tomorrow,
你得帮我打给订阅办公室
I'm gonna need you to call the subscription office for me.
行  我会的  我得走了
Yeah, will do. Look, I got to go.
我不想迟到
I don't want to be late.
祝你好运
Hey, good luck today!
-谢谢  -加油干
- Thanks. - Keep it up.
你努力工作的样子很棒
Hard work looks good on you.
本地律师  本地英雄
爬上20米高空救下广告牌工人
我看到有人有麻烦  直觉告诉我救人